<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>org.diary.Diary</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Diary</name>
  <summary>Encrypted personal diary</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      A small, secure diary. Every entry is automatically timestamped and
      stored encrypted with your master password (AES via Fernet, key derived
      with scrypt).
    </p>
    <p>Features:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Write entries with automatic timestamps and simple Markdown formatting</li>
      <li>Entry list with click to read and delete with confirmation</li>
      <li>Full-text search across all entries</li>
      <li>End-to-end encryption with a master password</li>
      <li>Portable single-file vault stored at a location you choose</li>
      <li>Menu bar to create, open (import) and export diary files</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">org.diary.Diary.desktop</launchable>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.2" date="2026-05-30">
      <description>
        <p>Visual overhaul and multi-diary management.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Modern welcome, unlock and create screens using Adwaita status pages</li>
          <li>Manage multiple diary vaults: switch, add and remove from a dedicated dialog</li>
          <li>Live Markdown preview while writing — formatting is applied as you type</li>
          <li>Formatting toolbar with icon buttons in linked groups</li>
          <li>Card-style editor area and constrained password field width</li>
          <li>Today's date shown as subtitle in the main header</li>
          <li>Entries heading with count in the sidebar</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>
          Portable single-file vault that you can store at any location of your
          choice. New welcome screen to create or open a diary, and a menu bar
          to create, open and export diary files. Flatpak-only build.
        </p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0" date="2026-05-29">
      <description>
        <p>First release: encrypted entries, search, GTK4 interface.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
